Eoin Dennehy

Lisbon, Portugal.

+353 (87) 4102372

eoinerd@gmail.com

Full stack software developer with 6 years of professional experience primarily in the eCommerce industry. Exceptional problem solver with a background in physics and applied mathematics, an aptitude for troubleshooting and ability to learn and master new skills, technologies or roles.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- Frontend: JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, HTML, Knockoutjs (some experience in Angular, React, and nodejs)
- Backend: C#, ASP.NET MVC, SQL Server, NHibernate, Entity Framework, IoC, NUnit
- CI/DI: TeamCity, OctopusDeploy
- Other: Visual Studio/Code, .NET Core, AutoMapper, ElasticSearch, Restful Web services, BitBucket, Jira, Git
- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/eoin-dennehy-41582631

WORK EXPERIENCE:

OCT 2018 – MAR 2019: Travelling and exploring around South East Asia. Also spent 6 months previous to that working remotely from Fortaleza in Brazil.

OCT 2013 – OCT 2018: MI9 Europe (Formerly MyWebGrocer and Buy4Now Technology Group), Sandyford Ind. Estate, Dublin, Ireland.

- Senior developer (core team) for major US eCommerce client Giant Eagle (C#, ASP.NET MVC, Javascript):
 - Developed the functionality to consume the clients APIs via Rest Web services, worked on both front-end and backend components, providing efficient and simple implementations with mobile responsiveness and accessibility in mind.
 - ➤ Helped implement the functionality of the search component using Elastic Search
 - Demonstrated JS skills by constantly refining and reducing the lines of unnecessary JS code by for example introducing Knockout.js for the particularly complex product details page
 - > Showed initiative and leadership by being involved in conference calls for requirements with the client.
 - Provided on-call support to provide troubleshooting for the client on issues with orders and customers
 - Spent the last 6 months of this position working remotely from Fortaleza Brazil, showing I am able and comfortable working in this manner.
- Senior developer for grocery client (SuperValu) implementing, troubleshooting and problem solving various issues (C#, JavaScript, ASP.NET Web Forms, SQL Server):
 - Investigating and resolving issues with payment gateway and orders in a timely manner
 - Developed a MVC 'business to business' application in conjunction with Dapper ORM and SimpleInjector IoC for a leading grocery retailer to set up certain customers with special accounts
 - ➤ Working closely with project manager to implement checkout and registration redesigns for some of our clients.
 - Mentored junior developers, explaining the development process and providing guidance and assistance whenever was necessary, thereby displaying teamwork and leadership. Also, constantly performed code reviews.
- Support developer for various general merchandise clients (Elverys Sports, Sam McCauleys Chemist, Curry's PC World, etc.)
 - ➤ Offboarded all clients to 3rd party payment gateway for PCI compliance
 - Investigating and resolving various support issues; for example, problems with customer orders, cosmetic front end bugs
 - Checkout and registration redesigns for some of our clients (Javascript, CSS, ASP.NET)
 - > Implementation of a .NET console application for processing an XML file of product data for a client (data-load)

JAN 2012 - OCT 2013: VNE Logisitics LTD, Greenogue Business Park, Rathcoole, Co. Dublin, Ireland.

- Working with a team of developers in providing support and development using ASP.NET Web Forms and SQL Server on our in-house supply-chain work management system allowing users to process an increased number of orders.
- Learned valuable front end skills (JS, HTML, CSS) developing a Short Term Let property Web application

EDUCATION:

2009 – 2010 M.Sc. - Maths Modelling and Scientific Computing, University College Cork, Ireland.

2004 – 2008 B.Sc.- Physics with Astrophysics, NUI Maynooth, Co. Kildare, Ireland.

INTERESTS & ACHIEVEMENTS

- Travelled to observatory near Marseilles in 2007 for final thesis observing open star clusters
- Languages I have been learning Portuguese for almost 2 years now
- Music both production and instrumental
- Keen interest in all things technology and science related
- Love learning different languages currently learning Python with Django.
- <u>eoinertravels.info</u>: a personal project implemented with ASP. NET Core and Angularjs Code: https://github.com/eoinerd/Travelogue

REFEREES:

- Dan Murphy, CTO, MI9 (Formerly MyWebGrocer), Sandyford, Dublin. danjmurphy@gmail.com
- Kieran Mulchrone, Senior lecturer, Department of Applied Mathematics, University College Cork.